<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medicine on </title>
    <link>/whodat_a.netlify.com/tags/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medicine on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 20:05:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/whodat_a.netlify.com/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration impacts Physicians Too</title>
      <link>/whodat_a.netlify.com/post/h1b_cartogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 20:05:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whodat_a.netlify.com/post/h1b_cartogram/</guid>
      <description>It might seem like long time ago now, but a few months ago, the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s attempt to ban immigrants from 6 muslim majority countries dominated the media cycle. The ban impacted people from all different walks of life, but physicians were given some special attention as there is not insignificant foreign physician workforce in the US, including 7000 from Iran, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, Syria and Yemen.
In April, Peter Kahn and Tova Gardin published a Research Letter in the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Duty Hours and the ACGME</title>
      <link>/whodat_a.netlify.com/post/acgme_work_hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 22:20:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whodat_a.netlify.com/post/acgme_work_hours/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who has spent time in the hospital, the not-so-well-kept secret is that residents are the ones you’re likely to see most often. About 25% hospitals have residents according to the ACGME, and percentage increases when you look Critical Access Hospitals.
Residents are the grunts of the medical world. They are full-fledged MDs who work worse hours for less pay than most nursing staff. Residents are the ones in the hospital overnight admitting patients and they are probably some of the first people you see in the morning as they run around trying to keep a lid on everything before the attending, or chief physician, to get to the hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>