<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 20:27:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="whodat_a.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>H1B visa holding Physicians</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/h1b_cartogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 20:27:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/h1b_cartogram/</guid>
      <description>Based off a &lt;a href=&#34;http://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2620160&#34;&gt;JAMA Research Letter&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; table of number and percent of active physicians holding H1B visas, I thought this this would make for an interesting visual representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Cartogram with R (and some outside help)</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/making_cartogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 20:15:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/making_cartogram/</guid>
      <description>#Respect Much of this tutorial could not have been accomplished without Frank Hecker&amp;rsquo;s Blog including a key function to create a dataframe from the shapefiles.
Some Background In April, Peter Kahn and Tova Gardin published a Research Letter in the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA). The article includes a table of number and percent of active physicians holding H1B visas. A few things surprised me in the map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Duty Hours and the ACGME</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/acgme_work_hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 22:20:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/acgme_work_hours/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who has spent time in the hospital, the not-so-well-kept secret is that residents are the ones you’re likely to see most often. About 25% hospitals have residents according to the ACGME, and percentage increases when you look Critical Access Hospitals.
Residents are the grunts of the medical world. They are full-fledged MDs who work worse hours for less pay than most nursing staff. Residents are the ones in the hospital overnight admitting patients and they are probably some of the first people you see in the morning as they run around trying to keep a lid on everything before the attending, or chief physician, to get to the hospital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tulane School of Medicine Alumni Map</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/alumni_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 21:23:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/alumni_map/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, Tulane provided us with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/viewer?mid=1AwGPAhlNgdtiVTwrO49VhXKxrEI&amp;amp;ll=36.3227501547167%2C-96.25223873124997&amp;amp;z=5&#34;&gt;map of recent Tulane Alumni and their residencies&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to improve upon the map and also learn some &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Leaflet&lt;/code&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration bans and Physicians</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/foreign-physicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/post/foreign-physicians/</guid>
      <description>My first day on my Surgery rotation was a whirlwind, filled with excitement at to be part of a surgery and have an idea about what is going on and the fear of getting pimped and not knowing the answer; but, honestly, my biggest fear was somehow managing to contaminate the field. Somehow I misread the numbers on the OR and went into the wrong room as a case was starting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Different Paths to a Fellowship</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/fellowship-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 21:39:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/fellowship-paths/</guid>
      <description>A while ago on &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/medicine&#34;&gt;r/medicine&lt;/a&gt; someone asked if there was a mapping of different fellowship paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans Healthcare Improvement Group Logo</title>
      <link>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/nohig_logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 17:47:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>whodat_a.netlify.com/projects/nohig_logo/</guid>
      <description>The New Orleans Healthcare Improvement Group (NOHIG) previously did not have a design so I started working on some ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>